Guide to the Murray Webb Latimer papers, 1930-1980 MS2082
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Railroad Retirement Board, 1934-1947; MS2082 Series 3; 5 Linear feet
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Retirement Claims, Miscl. Correspondence and Memoranda, undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: 440
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Prior Service, Miscl. Memoranda, undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: 446
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Retirment Claims, Prior Service Legislation: Bills, Memoranda, Correspondence, undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: 447
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -RR Retire. Bd., Retirement Claims Manual, EMPTY FOLDER, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Please note: this folder may be empty as noted in original finding aid. Original numbering system: 490
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Unemployment Insurance, Miscl. Correspondence and Memoranda, undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system:510
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Unemployment Insurance-Claims Taking, 1945 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: 515
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT POST WHEN M.W.L. WAS NO LONGER CHAIRMAN OF RR RETIREMENT BOARD: -Railway Labor Executives Assn. Correspondence with Latimer, Industrial-Be1ations Counselers, 1946 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: 541
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT POST: -Railroad Retirement Act, Question and Answers about Amendments, Pamphlets by Railway Labor Executive Assn, and RR Retirement Bd., 1946 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: 542
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Director of Research, Miscl. Correspondence and Memoranda, 1941 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: 605
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Post-War Retirement and Employment Memoranda, undated (Box 87, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: 607
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Research,Memoranda,and Tables on Military Service, undated (Box 87, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: 619
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Memoos, and Tables on Unemployment Insurance, 1945 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    Original numbering system: 620.1
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Bureau of Research, Information, and Statistics(BRIS),Memoranda on Maritime Unemployment Insurance, undated (Box 87, Folder 13)
    Original numbering system :623
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -BRIS, Momranda on Workmen's Compensation, undated (Box 87, Folder 14)
    Original numbering system: 640
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Returns to Service, Memoranda, undated (Box 87, Folder 15)
    Original numbering system: 660
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -BRIS, Miscl. Memoranda from Actuary, undated (Box 87, Folder 16)
    Original numbering system: 675
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -BRIS, Retirement Age Statistics, undated (Box 87, Folder 17)
    Original numbering system: 680
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -BL(?),Time Lost Legislation-Proposed Bills, Memoranda, Act., undated (Box 87, Folder 18)
    Original numbering system: 708
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Office of the General Council-Miscl. Memoranda and Correspondence, 1940 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    Original numbering system: 740.1
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Jurisdictional Docketts, undated (Box 87, Folder 20)
    Original numbering system: 750
  - RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD: -Labor Relations Officer-Memoranda Travel Itinerary, undated (Box 87, Folder 21)
    Original numbering system: 871
  - Railroad Retirement Board, undated (Box 88)
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Omnibus Bill-Correspondence and Memoranda, 1941 August-1943 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: 900
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Omnibus Bill; Coiranittee Prints,Explanations,Memoranda, 1942-1943 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: 901
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Omnibus Bill; Cost Memos, 1939 September-1943 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: 902
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Workmen's Compensation, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1938-1941 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: 905
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Workmen's Compensation, Drafts of Bills, 1940 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: 906
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Workmen's Compensation-Drafts of Bills and Committee Prints, 1941 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: 907
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Sickness Insurance; Correspondence and Memoranda, 1938-1942 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: 910
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Sickness Insurance, Miscl. Bills and Explanatory Memos, 1941 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: 911
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -78th Congress, 2nd Session, Correspondence and Memoranda, undated (Box 88, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: 920
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -78th Congress, 2nd Session,Chairman's Office Drafts of Replies to Inquiries on Proposed Amendments, undated (Box 88, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: 920.1
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -78th Congress, 2nd Session, Drafts Miscl., undated (Box 88, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: 921
  - Railroad Retirement Board, undated (Box 89)
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -78th Congress, 2nd Session Bills, Explanations, act., undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: 922
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE LEGISLATION (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -78th Congress, 2nd Session Cost memoranda, undated (Box 89, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: 923
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -79th Congress, lst Session, 1945 January-1945 December (Box 89, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: 924
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -79th Congress, lst and 2nd Session, 1946 January (Box 89, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: 924.a
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -79th Congress, lst Session; Final Reports to House and Senate Committee, undated (Box 89, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: 924.3
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Drafts, Miscl., undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: 925
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Bills and explanations, undated (Box 89, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: 926
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Cost Memoranda, undated (Box 89, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system:927
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Questions and Answers Booklet on H.R. 1362 and S293, undated (Box 89, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: 928
  - Railroad Retirement Board, undated (Box 90)
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Propaganda, Circulars, Act.H.R.1362 and S.293, undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: 930
  - RAILROAD SOCIAL INSURANCE BILL (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): Maritime Workmens Compensation Legislation,78th Congress, undated (Box 90, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: 961
  - INVESTIGATION ON RAILROAD EMPLOYEES INJURY AND DISEASE (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Correspondence, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: 990
  - INVESTIGATION ON RAILROAD EMPLOYEES INJURY AND DISEASE (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Instructions,Procedures,Forms and Form Letters, undated (Box 90, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: 991
  - INVESTIGATION ON RAILROAD EMPLOYEES INJURY AND DISEASE (RAILROAD RETIREMENT BOARD): -Legislation, undated (Box 90, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: 992
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -75th Congress,3rd Session and 76th Congress,1st Session-Bills,Memoranda,Correspondence, undated (Box 90, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: 1030
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -76th Congress, 3rd Session-Bills, Drafts, Hearings, and Report, undated (Box 90, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: 1031
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -1967th Congress, 3rd Session, Memoranda and Correspondence, undated (Box 90, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: 1031.1
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -Gentral Records Section, Bureau of Marine Inspection and Navigation-Memorandum and Exhibits, undated (Box 90, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: 1031.3
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -77th Congress, lst Session, Bills, Hearings Reports, undated (Box 90, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: 1032
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -77th Congress, lst Session-Memoranda and Correspondence, undated (Box 90, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: 1032.1
  - Railroad Retirement Board, undated (Box 91)
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -78th Congress-1st Session,Bills & Reports, undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: 1033
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -78th Congress-2nd Session,Memoranda,Correspondence, undated (Box 91, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: 1033.4
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -78th Congress-2nd Session,Committee Prints,Reports and Bills, undated (Box 91, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system:1033.4
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -78th Congress-2nd Session-Drafts of Memoranda, undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system:1033.5
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -79th Congress-1st Session, Bills, Hearings and Reports, undated (Box 91, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: 1034
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -1st Session, Memoranda and Correspondence, undated (Box 91, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: 1034.1
  - MARITIME UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (RR RETIREMENT BD.): -Drafts of Memoranda, undated (Box 91, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: 1034.2
- Publications, Circa 1930- Circa 1980; MS2082 Series 4; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains individual issues of various journals, newsletters, bulletins, and other publication forms. These publications relate to economics, railroad retirement, health, social security, labor, and aging. Many of these publications come from the corporations and organizations that are present in series one.
  - AMSTAT News American Statistical Ass., undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-2
  - Monthly Economic Letter, Issued by First National City Bank, New York, undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-3
  - Bests Insurance News Digest, undated (Box 92, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: P-4
  - Publications, undated (Box 93)
  - Business Statistics Commerce Dept. and Others, undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-195
  - Mid American Outlook Business Bulletin, CleveTrust Corporation, undated (Box 93, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-196
  - Business in Brief Issued by Chase Manhattan Bank, undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system :P-7
  - Buisness Report, Economic Report,Financial Report Manufacturers Hanover Trust, undated (Box 93, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: P-8
  - Treasury Department, Pension Trust Division Information Service, undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: P-9
  - Railroad Retirement and Unemployment Insurance, Monthl Benefit-Satistics, undated (Box 93, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: P-11a
  - Railroad Retirement Publications, undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: P-1 lb
  - Monthly Vital Statistics Report and Advance Data, Issued by National Center for Health Statistics, undated (Box 93, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: P-12A
  - Publications, undated (Box 94)
  - Monthly Vital Statistics Report and Advance Data National Center For Health Statistics, undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-12B
  - HEALTH EDUCATION AND WELFARE SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION: -Actuarial Note, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-12.1
  - HEALTH EDUCATION AND WELFARE SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION: -Analytical Note, undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: P-12.2
  - HEALTH EDUCATION AND WELFARE SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION: -Research and Statistics Note, undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: P-12.3
  - HEALTH EDUCATION AND WELFARE SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION: -Health Insurance Statistics, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: P-12.4
  - HEALTH EDUCATION AND WELFARE SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION: -Monthly Benefit Statistics, undated (Box 94, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: P-12.5
  - Publications, undated (Box 95)
  - Aging, Senior Citizens Monthly, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-13
  - Dail Tax Report, undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-13.1
  - Seasonal Ad'ustment Factors Federal Reserve Board, undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: P-14
  - Public Health Service Depratment, H.E.W., undated (Box 95, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: P-15
  - Health Security News, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: P-16
  - Emphasis: Employer, Labor Summary, D.C. Department of Manpower, undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: P-17
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield Publications, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: P-18
  - Statistical Bulletin Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., undated (Box 95, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: P-19
  - Government Affairs Bulletin and Group 0perational Procedures Metropolitan Life insurance Co., undated (Box 95, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: P-19.1
  - Gerontological Society Newsletters and Other Gerontological Material, undated (Box 95, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: P-20
  - Geriatric Focus, undated (Box 95, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: P-21
  - Group Health Ass.,G.H.A. News and Miscl., undated (Box 95, Folder 12)
    Original numbering system: P-21.1
  - Publications, undated (Box 96)
  - Department of Labor, Miscl., undated (Box 96, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-22
  - Department of Labor Office of Information, News, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-22a
  - Department of Labor, Manpower Admistration, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: P-23a2
  - Miscl. Publications; Ozark Airlines Inc Retirement Plan; Amstat News(one Issue); Symposium of Variable Annuities, Wharton School, U. of Pa., undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: P-27
  - Industrial Relations Research Association Series (News Letter), undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: P-28
  - International Dimensions Atlantic Economic Society, undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: P28.1
  - Bureau of Employment Security-Pennsylvanian Dept. of Labor and Industry, undated (Box 96, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: P-29
  - Employment Trends, New York State/Massachusetts 'Trends, undated (Box 96, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: P-30
  - Emphasis Tillinghast, Nelson, and Warren, Inc., undated (Box 96, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: P-31
  - Steel Facts, American Iron and Steel Institute, undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: P-33
  - AFL-CIO Newsletter and ;Bert Seidham, Work Ethic and Welfare Reform Statement of AFL-CIO Executive Council, undated (Box 96, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: P-33.1
  - The AFL-CIO American Federationist, undated (Box 96, Folder 12)
    Original numbering system: P-33.2
  - Publications, undated (Box 97)
  - Memo From COPE (Commitee on Political Edueation, AFL-CIO), undated (Box 97, Folder 1)
    Original numbering system: P-33.3
  - Viewpoint, Industrial Union Department Quarterly, undated (Box 97, Folder 2)
    Original numbering system: P-33.4
  - I.U.D. Bulletin, undated (Box 97, Folder 3)
    Original numbering system: P-33.5
  - ULLICO Bulletin (United Labor Life Insurance Co.), undated (Box 97, Folder 4)
    Original numbering system: P-33.6
  - Actuarial Publications-General, undated (Box 97, Folder 5)
    Original numbering system: P-34
  - The American Academy Of Actuaries Newsletter, undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
    Original numbering system: P-34.a
  - Enrolled Actuaries Report, American Academy of Actuaries, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
    Original numbering system: P-34b
  - The Actuarial Review Casualty Actuarial Society, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
    Original numbering system: P-34.c
  - Management News and Some Small Publications American Management Association, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
    Original numbering system: P-35
  - Harvard Information, undated (Box 97, Folder 10)
    Original numbering system: P-36
  - Internal Revenue Publication Employee Pension Annuity Profit-Sharing Stock Bonus, and Bond Purchase Plans Including Plans For Self Employed Individuals, undated (Box 97, Folder 11)
    Original numbering system: P-38
  - Edward Friend and Co. Quarterly Newsletter, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
    Original numbering system: P-39
  - AFL-CIO Miscl. Material, undated (Box 97, Folder 13)
    Original numbering system: P-40
  - Statments, Reports Adopted by the AFL-CIO Executive Council, undated (Box 97, Folder 14)
    Original numbering system: P-40.1
  - Washington Statistical Society Newsletter, undated (Box 97, Folder 15)
    Original numbering system: P-41
  - Railroad retirement systems in the United States [1/2], 1938; Series 4 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Railroad retirement systems in the United States [2/2], 1938; Series 4 (Box 139, Folder 2)
- Tabular studies, undated; MS2082 Series 5; 1 Linear feet (Box 98, Box 99)
  This series is unprocessed. The series contains tables. These tables relate to employment issues primarily for the railroad industry. The series has topics such as pension plans, annuity tables, dismissal compensation, and unemployment benefits.
- Railroad companies, undated; MS2082 Series 6; 2 Linear feet (Box 100, Box 137, Box 136, Box 135, Box 134, Box 133, Box 120, Box 111, Box 110, Box 107, Box 106, Box 105, Box 104, Box 103, Box 102, Box 101, Box 138, Box 128, Box 127, Box 130, Box 129, Box 132, Box 131, Box 108, Box 109, Box 122, Box 121, Box 124, Box 123, Box 126, Box 125)
  This series is unprocessed. The series contains material related to various railroad companies. Some of the companies include among others Baltimore & Ohio, Chesapeake & Ohio, Erie RR, Lehigh & Hudson River, Minneapolis & St. Louis, N. Y. Susquehanna & Western, South Omaha Terminal, and Texas City Terminal.